Speaker 1: 78% of Americans now view fast food as a luxury, according to a new study from LendingTree, which polls Americans about their financial situation.
Speaker 1: In recent videos, I've talked about the bottom falling out of consumer spending, with lower-income buyers cutting back on everything from McDonald's to Kraft mac and cheese, a millennial's best friend.
Speaker 1: It turns out that's not just the bottom, that is, the whole Kahuna burger is fully. 4 in 5 Americans now say that fast food is a luxury, and they are cutting back.
Speaker 1: In case you're wondering why, before the pandemic, a Big Mac cost $3.99. Today, it's $8.29.
Speaker 1: A Chipotle chicken burrito could be had for $6.50 before Biden's inflation. Now, it is $10.70.
Speaker 1: Chicken nuggets and the basic cheeseburger have doubled or even tripled.
Speaker 1: This has driven a typical family meal at, say, McDonald's, from $35 or $40 to $60 or $70.
Speaker 1: According to the survey of 2,000 Americans, 3 in 4 used to eat fast food at least once a week, but a majority, 62%, are now eating it less because of prices, with 65% of them reported being shocked by fast food prices.
Speaker 1: As you'd expect, people who are cutting back the most include parents with young kids, Gen Z, so those under 30, and women.
Speaker 1: But even among high-income Americans, more than half are eating less fast food, which, granted, might not be a terrible thing health-wise,
Speaker 1: but presumably they are cutting back even more on full-service dining in a country where restaurants and food service employ 14 million people.
Speaker 1: As LendingTree notes, quote, the days of using fast food to help make ends meet are long gone.
Speaker 1: McDonald's went from a little helper on the budget to a little hole in the budget.
Speaker 1: So what happened?
Speaker 1: Well, the Fed printed $6 trillion.
Speaker 1: The federal government spent $8 trillion in deficits, all with an assist from regulations, industrial-scale shoplifting, thanks to Huggs First prosecutors, and, of course, the occasional riot.
Speaker 1: This clown show of government negligence has driven fast food prices up by between 41%, going by the Fed's data, to 55% going by actual fast food menus.
Speaker 1: While basic items like chicken nuggets or cheeseburgers, which are staples for the poor, have gone up 200% or more.
Speaker 1: I've mentioned in recent videos that fast food, specifically the Big Mac, has long been a standard inflation measure.
Speaker 1: In fact, it's more trusted by financial markets than government statistics.
Speaker 1: So if inflation has been not 20% or 30% as government statisticians say, but the 40% to 50% that fast food says, it means we could be a whole lot poorer than we think.
Speaker 1: And if so, going by the rest of the statistics, that misery is falling squarely on the lower, middle, and the working class, who are bereft of Fed-pumped assets to shield them from money printing and money spending orgies in Washington.
Speaker 1: So what's next, brought to you by Unchained.com.
Speaker 1: When economic historians try to see through the fog of data, we focus on a few key numbers, things like life expectancy, house size, car ownership rate, and eating out versus making it home.
Speaker 1: Starting in 2000, accelerating since 2008, across the board, these indicators are either grinding to a halt or they're actually reversing.
Speaker 1: The elite cannot see it because it's not happening to them.
Speaker 1: They're doing better than ever ensconced in their trillion-dollar money siphons.
Speaker 1: The regular Americans who pay their salary who have to cut back on the happy meals.
Speaker 1: Okay, we'll be watching.
Speaker 1: See you next time.